

Muhammad Ismail

Sr. Full Stack Developer

+923347075645

link2ismail@gmail.com 🔀

Multan Road, Lahore Pakistan

linkedin.com/in/ismailansaribwp in



About

Having 9+ years of experience in all facets of web development, from meeting with clients to discuss their goals, research & analysis, design, development, testing and taking feedback to improve the system. Doesn't stick to the given instructions but thinks out of the box to create a better product. Good analytical and debugging skills. Having proven record of work under pressure and adaptable to new technologies.

Key Skills

- PHP
- Laravel
- MYSQL
- IMTH
- CSS
- React JS
- Next.JS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- API's Development
- Linux
- GIT
- ElasticSearch

Work Experience

2019-2023 Ilsa Interactive, Lahore

4 years

- Developed the B2C app using React with NEXT.js
- Team Management as review work / code and assigned new tasks and deployments of their work
- Wrote the API for Hotel booking app
- Improved the User Experience of the App via using the concurrent APIS requests and showed the prices as fetched from suppliers on the app also made sure the cheapest one is selected if same hotel is available from multiple suppliers
- Usage of LARAVEL Schedules, Jobs and Queues
- DB Optimization like usage of Indexes and denormalization / normalization of the data where required
- · Usage of Elastic Search for fast search

2016-2019 DataMonster, Lahore

2.5 years

- Worked on Amazon MWS Reporting and Analysis App, Learned LARAVEL, VueJs by myself and developed the multi form Authentication module in VueJs and Laravel used Stripe Payment Gateway for method
- Wrote PHP LARAVEL SDK Libraries for amazon MWS applied the OOP best approaches usage of PHPUNIT and other testing techniques to improve a system
- Performed automated testing tasks and developed complex features routinely.

Xoho Tech (GeeksChicago), Lahore 2015-2016

1.25 years

- Worked on WP network based web app named Serving Sites. Integrate new features, plugin customization and handle responsive layouts of templates. ServingSites
- Developed a mobile app prototype in phonegap (Serving Sites) having features like WordPress admin front-end developed in AngularJS and Bootstrap while used WP Rest API in back-end.

Barqsol Technologies, Lahore 2013-2014

1.5 years

- · Developed an Ajax based web app for insurance system major features are customer management, Agent management, commission management, PDF receipts generating and email notifications.
- Worked on social web app named Field-Trip developed the modules like matching events and activities on the basis of user interest, Admin panel CRUDS, Events and Activities Searching and Listing GRID and Map view (Google Map API) and payment module for user accounts using Stripe.

Education

BSIT(07-11) | CGPA 3.04 / 4.0 Islamia University, Bahawalpur

FSC (04-07) | 65% S.E College, Bahawalpur

Reference

Jamshaid Sadiq

Project Manager, ILSA Interactive

Phone: +923106233969